Yigit Dincsoy

av.yigitdincsoy@gmail.com, (902) 223-9646

Availability: From April 24, 2023 Halifax, NS

I am a software developer with 1 year of experience, with specialization in web technologies such as Javascript & React, and video game development with Gamemaker Studio with a portfolio of multiple released products.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Lawyer / Trainee Lawyer

2021 - 2022

Izmir Bar Association, Turkey

I performed a one-year legal traineeship at the Turkish Ministry of Justice and regional law firms.

Software Developer

2018 - 2019

Studio Attic Salt, Turkey

- I worked on multiple video game projects that were developed with Gamemaker Studio and released on Steam.
- I have project management & marketing experience in a tech start-up environment.

EDUCATION

Nova Scotia Community College

2022 - 2023

Graduate Certificate, Full Stack Application Development

Halifax, NS

- Web Development: React, Express, Node.js, HTML5, CSS & SCSS
- Software Development: Javascript/ES6, Electron, React Native
- Database Technologies: SQLite, MySQL, MongoDB
- Experience with OWASP Top 10, Git & Jest

Yasar University

Sep 2016 - May 2020

Bachelor of Laws (Turkish / English)

Izmir, Turkey

- IENG 110 Probability and Statistics, ECON 120 Essentials of Economics, UFND 030 Design Culture
- LAWS 379 English Legal Writing and Textual Analysis, MATH 151 Mathematics for Lawyers

PROJECTS

- Math for Kids, Mathemagic (2021), Released on Google Playstore, 2000+ Users
- The Metamorphosis (Visual Novel Adaptation, 2020), Released on Steam, 500+ Sales
- Misadventures of Laura Silver (2019), Released on Steam, 9000+ Sales & 40.000+ Users

CERTIFICATIONS

- Project Management Institute Agile / KICKOFF
- British Council IELTS 8 / Advanced English
- International Qualifications Assessment Service (Province of Alberta): Bachelor's degree equivalency

AWARDS

- What's Your Challenge 2023, REDspace & NSCC (Student competition aimed at solving industry problems)
- Your Goals, Your Future 2022 Student Award, Issued by NSCC
- Yogscast 2019 Humble Bundle Jingle Jam Participation (Misadventures of Laura Silver)
- International Digital Game And Entertainment Expo, GameX Awards (Istanbul 2019),
 Misadventures of Laura Silver, "Best Turkish Independent Game"
- TyranoBuilder Spring Game Jam Issued by Nyu Media (2017), True Odds, "Honorable Mention"

